

ALEXANDRA VOROBYOVA

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality: Russian Mobile: +7 (960) 515-59-98

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm an enthusiastic professional with several years experience in frontend developing and UX. I am goal oriented. I create effective websites paying special attention to the appearance, content, functionality, usability and search engine optimization. Here are just a few examples of my latest work:

www.m.tehnosila.ru

www.zhivagobank.ru

www.promobank.ru

EDUCATION

2014 GeekBrains, Moscow

Course of Swift Language Programming

2013 Moscow coding school, Moscow

Advanced HTML and CSS course

2002 – 2007 Obninsk State Technical University for Nuclear Power Engineering

B.A. (equivalent) in Applied Mathematics and Programming

EMPLOYMENT

2008 to date

«Forth Rome.Design» Ltd., 4rome.ru, Obninsk

Frontend developer, content manager

For the first year, I worked as a content manager preparing texts and optimizing photos for publishing on websites. I also trained our clients to use the self-made CMS. I then moved on to prototyping websites in Axure and creating simple HTML and CSS layouts.

For the past few years I have worked as a frontend developer. My responsobilies include:

- Front end development of websites using HTML(5)/Jade, CSS(3)/Less/Stylus, Javascript/jQuery/Backbone
- Creating HTML/CSS markups for e-Newsletters
- Supporting websites based on Bitrix Platform and YII Framework
- Optimizing web sites for desktops, tablets and mobile devices (iOS and Android)
- Training junior staff in understanding WebStandarts and using best web developer practices
- Optimizing websites according to SEO principles

2013 - 2014

promobank.ru, Moscow

Frontend developer, freelance

I worked closely with backend programmer to find better ways for creating an effective website. I used HTML5, jQuery, jQuery UI and Sass.

2012 - 2013

estorico.com, Obninsk

Frontend developer, freelance

I worked as part of web developer's group. My responsibility was to ensure that our HTML and CSS/Sass code was clean and well-structured. I also developed javascript code using jQuery, BackboneJs, AngularJs (basic level). I worked closely with web designer, suggested the UX desicions for clean and functional interface.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Technologies

HTML(5)/Jade, CSS(3)/BEM/Bootstrap/960Grid, LESS, Sass, Stylus, Javascript/ jQuery/BackboneJS/Underscore.js, W3C Standards and Accessibility Aware, Responsive Web Design, Cross browser compatibility, Progressive enhancement, Responsible markup, Photoshop, Sketch.

IDEs

Webstorm, Sublime, Cloud9

Tools

Gulp, Git, BrowserStack, StackOverflow

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Languages: Native Russian. Fluent English
- Computing: Advanced knowledge of both PC and Mac platforms
- Software: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Microsoft Word

INTERESTS

I enjoy playing gitar and piano. I practice yoga 3 times a week. I'm keen to keep up to date with the latest news, reading such websites as Smashing Magazine and AlistApart.